DeVault, Ileen Research Files for "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Turn-of the Century Pittsburgh" /4213
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Ileen DeVault Research Files for "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Turn-of the Century Pittsburgh"
1979-2011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
DeVault, Ileen
/4213
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Papers, nonfiction.
8051478
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 14, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 04, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Ileen DeVault is Professor of Labor History at Cornell University's ILR School in Ithaca, NY, where she teaches classes on labor and working-class history. She is also one of the co-chairs of the Equity at Work Initiative of The Worker Institute at Cornell, as well as a member of The Worker Institute Executive Committee. She is the author of "Sons and Daughters of Labor" and "United Apart: Gender and the Rise of Craft Unionism," as well as articles. Her current research is on issues involving the impact of workers' family status on their workplace experiences between 1880 and 1930 and in the present.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4213 mf: Ileen DeVault Research Files for "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Turn-of the Century Pittsburgh" on Microfilm /4213 P: Ileen DeVault Research Files for "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Turn-of the Century Pittsburgh" Photographs
DeVault, Ileen A.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8051478
- Commercial Dept. Collective Biography, ID#s 001-1199 (see attached description). (Box 1)
  - Coding Instructions for 1900 Census (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Information on Emanuel Schillo (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The National Labor Tribune Xeroxes (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Responses to Pittsburgh Ad, November 1987, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Research on Individuals from 1900 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fathers Traced (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Research on individuals
  - Pittsburgh and Allegheny Street and Ward Directories and Newspaper Xeroxes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alphabetical Listing of Occupational Codes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    March 1988
  - 15th Ward (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Research on individuals from 1895 - 1915
  - 16th Ward (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Research on individuals, 1895 - 1915
  - 17th Ward (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 31st Ward (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 32nd Ward (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 35th Ward (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 001 - 199, Individual Research 1895 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 200 - 299, Individual Research 1900 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 300 - 399, Individual Research, 1900 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 400 - 499, Individual Research 1905-1915 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 500 - 599, Individual Research 1905 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 600 - 699, Individual Research 1895-1915 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 700 - 799, Individual Research, 1895 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 800 - 899, Individual Research 1895 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 900 - 999, Individual Research 1900 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1000 - 1099, Individual Research, 1900 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1100 - 1199, Individual Research, 1900 - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Biographies for ID#1200-1875, 1900 census for area Wards, misc records. (Box 2)
  - 1200 - 1299, Research on Individuals 1900 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1300 - 1399, Research on Individuals 1900 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1400 - 1499, Research on Individuals 1900 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1500 - 1599, Research on Individuals 1900 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1600 - 1699, Research on Individuals 1905 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1700 - 1799, Research on Individuals 1905 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1800 - 1899, Research on Individuals 1900 - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Residents of the 15th Ward (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Residents of the 16th Ward (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Residents of the 17th Ward (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Residents of the 31st Ward (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Residents of the 35th Ward (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reject ed Individuals for Research (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Coding Instructions for 1900 Census (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Comparative Census Data, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - City Directory Data (CDIRIS.DATA) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Marriage Records (MARRECS.DATA), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1900 Census (CENSUS.DATA), 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - City Directory Data (CDIR05.DATA), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Merge Files: Schmar.SPSS, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - SCHTOWK.SPSS/SCHTOAD.SPSS, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - School Records (PITTCD.DATA), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Appendix on Data (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Data, computer printouts. (Box 3)
  - "The 1910 Federal Population Census: National Archives Trust Board" Washington, DC 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - COMPCEN.DATA Final Completed File, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    February 15 1987
  - All Compiled Data on Pittsburgh Individuals, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    November 21 1979
  - Sibling Employment and Home Ownership, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Occupational Status and Economic Situation by Sex and in General, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ethinicity and Economic Situation by Sex, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Working Class Students and Portrait of Students Entering Comm. Department in 1900, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Working Class Children and Miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    November 4 1984
  - Test Coding Page for Pittsburgh Individuals, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 4 Comparative Tables, Contains Errors, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    July 5 1989
  - Computer Print-Outs for Home Ownership, Nativity and Ethnicity, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    July 1989
  - Compiled Data on Pittsburgh Individuals, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    October 31 1979
  - Data Regarding Home Ownership, Geography and other Factors, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - More Occupational Data, 1979-1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Marriage, Geography and Occupation Data, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - City Directory Data, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    August 12 1980
  - Marriage, Geographical, and Urban/Suburban Data, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Information on Students, Schools, and Amount of Schooling, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Geography and Wards, City Directory, First Occupation by Sex, Widows, Age at Marriage, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Data by Chapter, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Data, computer printouts. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Weighted and Sorted Data, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kids' Occupation Data, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kids' Occupation Data, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marriage Records Data (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Students Leaving Without Graduation in 1900, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Leaving Without Graduation in 1900 Crosstabs, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - No Occupation and Sibling Occupation by Father's Occupation. No Graduation in 1900 Frequency, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Students Leaving Communications Department in 1900, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Includes mistakes
  - Portrait of Students Entering Communications Department in 1900, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Girls' Siblings Occupations (1-4), 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Boy's Siblings (1-5), Miscellaneous Siblings, General Siblings Occupations, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Unskilled, Skilled, White Collar and Proprietor Kids' Occupations, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Information Regarding Siblings, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Information Regarding Ethnicity and Home Ownership, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Information Regarding Occupations, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Frequencies of Ethnicities and Social Statuses, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Frequencies for Residence, General, Schooling, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Information on Occupations, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Siblings for Chapter 4 and Other Miscellaneous Information, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Data, computer printouts. (Box 5)
  - Yale Computer Center Miscellaneous Documents, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - FORTRAN Coding Forms for the Individuals (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - FORTRAN Coding Form for the Individuals (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Census Data Information, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Age at Marriage and Marriage's Effects on Occupation, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Data Regarding Occupation, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Data and Computer Practice, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Information Regarding WSCRIPT, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - FORTRAN Coding Forms and other Programming Information, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Information on Occupations, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Work, Demographic, and Ward Data, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Weighted Data, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Chapter Tables, Miscellaneous, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous CDIR15 and Other Census Documents and Data, 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Marriage Record Data, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Data Table Appendix and Miscellaneous Computer Runs (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Last Folder (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Pittsburgh School District Sub-District Minutes, Pittsburgh Dispatch, Book manuscript & related correspondence. (Box 6)
  - "Sub-District Minutes", 2005-2011 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Allen Luckey, Mt. Washington
  - "Sub-District Minutes", 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Howard Lawrence, Washington
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sons and Daughters of Labor Documents, Miscellaneous Tables, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - DeVault Documents, Computer-Related, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Book Table of Contents, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cornell University Press Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Book Front Matter, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Reader's Reports, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - My Manuscript Revision Thoughts, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Give the Boys a Trade: Gender and Job Choice in the 1890's", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Things for Future Chapters, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Book Tables (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Book Correspondence and Graphics, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work In Pittsburgh, 1870's - 1910's", 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    A Dissertation Presented to the Faculty of the Graduate School of Yale University by Ileen A. DeVault, December 1985
  - "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Turn-of-the-Century Pittsburgh" (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Ileen A. DeVault, Original Copy
  - "Sons and Daughters of Labor" Individual Parts (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondences with the Catherwood Library, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "Business Education: A Retrospective", 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    South-Western Publishing Co.; March 1978
  - "Work and Honor: The Daughters of Pittsburgh's Skilled Workers", 1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Ileen A. DeVault, Yale University
  - "Sons and Daughters of Labor: Class and Clerical Work in Turn-of-the-Century Pittsburgh", 1990 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Ileen A. DeVault, Cornell University Press, Duplicate Manuscript
  - Correspondence Regarding Illustrations and Photographs for Manuscript, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Pittsburgh and Allegheny Directory 1905" (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Xerox
  - Maps and Figures for Manuscript (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Sent to Peter Agree